Guide to the New-York Historical Society Original Building Planning & Construction Records 1848-1946 NYHS-RG 3
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Central Park West Construction: Expansion, 1925-1946; 68.48 Linear feet
  - Subseries IV.A. General Project Documents, 1925-1926, 1935-1939; 3.96 Linear feet in 9.5 document boxes
    - Specifications (Set 2-Numbered) (1 of 4), 1937 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Specifications (Set 2-Numbered) (2 of 4), 1937 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Specifications (Set 2-Numbered) (3 of 4), 1936-1938 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Specifications (Set 2-Numbered) (4 of 4), 1937-1938 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Specifications (Set 3-Complete, Bound), 1936-1938 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Sub-Contractors. A.B. See Elevator Co. (Book Stack Elevator), 1937 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Sub-Contractors. Achilles Construction Co. (Steel Buildings), 1937 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Sub-Contractors. Allen Automatic, Inc. (Slide-up Door), 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Sub-Contractors. Anderson Brick & Supply Co. inc (Masonry Materials), 1936 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Sub-Contractors. Anti-Hydro Waterproofing Co., 1937 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Sub-Contractors. Arnold H. Warmolts (Leather Door Covering), 1938 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Sub-Contractors. Baker, Smith & Co., Inc. (Heating & Ventilating), 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Sub-Contractors. Bethlehem Steel Co. (Reinforcing Steel), 1937 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Sub-Contractors. C.E. Halback & Co. (Bronze Work, Etc.), 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Sub-Contractors. Campbell Metal Window Corp. (Steel Windows), 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Sub-Contractors. Chapman Metal Products Co. Inc. (Kalamein Work), 1937 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Sub-Contractors. Chesebro-Whitman Co. Inc. (Steel Hoist Towers), 1937 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Sub-Contractors. Chittenden Lumber Co., 1938 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Sub-Contractors. Clarence L. Smith Foundation Corp. (Sheet Piling & Excavation), 1937 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Sub-Contractors. Contractors Glass Co. Inc. (Glass & Glazing), 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Sub-Contractors. Cornell Iron Works, Inc. (Rolling Shutter Door), 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Sub-Contractors. Cranford & Joseph, Inc. (Tile Work), 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Sub-Contractors. Del Turco Bros. Inc. (Terrazzo & Mosaic Work), 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Sub-Contractors. Edwd. F. Caldwell & Co. Inc. (Lighting Fixtures), 1938 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Sub-Contractors. Ernest Capelle (Flag Poles), 1938 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Sub-Contractors. Federal Seaboard Terra Cotta Corp., 1937 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Sub-Contractors. Ferro Art Co. Inc. (Reading Room Lighting Fixtures), 1938 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Sub-Contractors. Formica Insulation Co., 1938 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Sub-Contractors. Frank Scolaro Marble Co. Inc. (Interior Marble Work), 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Sub-Contractors. General Bronze Corp., 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Sub-Contractors. General Builders Supply Corp. (Masonry Materials), 1937 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Sub-Contractors. Gunn Decorating Co. Inc. (Painting & Finishing), 1938-1939 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Sub-Contractors. Hanley Co. Inc. (Face Brick), 1937 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Sub-Contractors. Hohmann & Barnard Inc. (Water Bars), 1937 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Sub-Contractors. J.J. Fisher Co. Inc. (Roofing & Sheet Metal Work), 1937-1939 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Sub-Contractors. Jacobson & Co. Inc. (Metal Lath, Furring & Plastering), 1938 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Sub-Contractors. John A. McCarthy & Co. Inc. (Masonry Materials), 1937 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Sub-Contractors. John L. Goss Corp. (Granite & Granite Work), 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Sub-Contractors. M.F.C. Shoring & Foundation Co. Inc. (Sidewalk Bridge), 1937 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Sub-Contractors. MacNutt, Watts & Tankard Inc. (Electrical Work), 1937-1939 (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Sub-Contractors. Materials Delivery Corp. (Masonry Material), 1937 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Sub-Contractors. Mosler Safe Co. (Vault Door), 1937 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Includes two photographs of Mosler vault #0-1941.
    - Sub-Contractors. Ostrander & Eshleman Inc. (Finished Hardware), 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Sub-Contractors. Pagano Granite Corp. (Granite Sill), 1938 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Sub-Contractors. Paramount Window Cleaning Service, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Sub-Contractors. Peelle Co. Inc. (Freight Elevator Doors), 1937 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Sub-Contractors. R.E. Carrick & Co. Inc (Concrete Arches, Sidewalk, Fireproofing), 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Sub-Contractors. Ricci Studio (Models), 1937 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Sub-Contractors. Robert W. Hunt Co. (Concrete Testing), 1937 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Sub-Contractors. Snead & Co. (Book Stacks), 1935-1938 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Includes correspondence, specifications, a sketch by Walker & Gillette of the book stack floor plan, blueprint drawing # 30672 by Snead of sample shelves, Snead & Co.'s marketing brochure, photographs of Snead's shelving at Columbia University, University of Utah, and the University of Texas, and two identical photographs of the exterior of the National Archives building (Washington, DC).
    - Sub-Contractors. Spencer, White & Prentis Inc. (Pipe Pile Foundations), 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Sub-Contractors. Sprague & Henwood (Test Boring), 1936 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Sub-Contractors. Storm Flooring Co. Inc. (Finished Wood Floors), 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Sub-Contractors. Strawbridge & Clothier (Asphalt Tile), 1937 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Sub-Contractors. Structural Waterproofing Inc., 1937 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Sub-Contractors. Superior Steel Door & Trim Co. Inc. (Hollow Metal Work), 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Sub-Contractors. T.P. McLoughlin Inc. (Plumbing), 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Sub-Contractors. Taylor-Fichter Steel Construction Co. Inc. (Structural Steel), 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Sub-Contractors. Transit Mix Concrete Co. Inc., 1937 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Sub-Contractors. United Hoisting Co. Inc. (Erection of Hoist), 1937 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Sub-Contractors. Van Brunt Bros. Inc. (Lintels), 1937 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Sub-Contractors. Vernon Lumber Corp., 1937 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Sub-Contractors. Walsh Wrecking Corp. (Building & Wall Demolitions), 1937 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Sub-Contractors. Westinghouse Electric Elevator Co., 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Sub-Contractors. William Somerville Inc. (Cabinet Work), 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Walker & Gillette Expense Certifications, 1936-1939 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      This folder includes the certifications to N-YHS from Walker & Gillette, confirming the appropriateness of the payment applications submitted by the construction contractors. The support documentation for certificate #1, payable to George Hollerith, is in the Walker & Gillette correspondence folder above. The support documentation for certificate #26, payable to Edwd. F. Caldwell & Co., is in the folder above under that sub-contractor's name. All other certificates, through #27, were payable to Turner Construction; the correspondence, supporting documents, and payment applications from Turner related to each certificate are in the following folders.
    - Turner Payment Application 1 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 2, 1937 February (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Turner Payment Application 2 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 3, 1937 March (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Turner Payment Application 3 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 4, 1937 April (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Turner Payment Application 4 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 5, 1937 May (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Turner Payment Application 5 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 6, 1937 June (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Turner Payment Application 6 / Walker & Gillette Certificates 7, 8, and 9, 1937 July (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Turner Payment Application 7 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 10, 1937 August (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Turner Payment Application 8 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 11, 1937 September (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Turner Payment Application 9 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 12, 1937 October (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Turner Payment Application 10 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 13, 1937 November (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Turner Payment Application 11 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 14, 1937 December (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Turner Payment Application 12 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 15, 1938 January (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Turner Payment Application 13 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 16, 1938 February (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Turner Payment Application 14 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 17, 1938 March (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Turner Payment Application 15 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 18, 1938 April (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Turner Payment Application 16 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 19, 1938 May (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Turner Payment Application 17 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 20 and 21, 1938 June (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Turner Payment Application 18 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 22, 1938 July (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Turner Payment Application 19 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 23, 1938 August (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Turner Payment Application 20 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 24, 1938 September (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Turner Payment Application 21 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 25, 1938 October (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Turner Payment Application 22 / Walker & Gillette Certificate 27, 1939 February (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Packing List. Almanacs, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Packing List. Annex, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Packing List. Basement, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Packing List. Basement House, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Packing List. Charles Allen Munn Collection, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Packing List. China & Glass, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Packing List. Contents of Metal Room - New York Room, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Packing List. Directories, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Packing List. 8th & 9th Floor Stacks & Library Floor Heraldry, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Packing List. Gallery, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Packing List. Imprint Section, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Packing List. King Collection, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Packing List. Manhattan Storage, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Packing List. Manuscripts, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Packing List. Miniatures, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Packing List. Miscellaneous, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Packing List. Nadelman Museum, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Packing List. Naval History Room & Naval History Manuscripts, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Packing List. N-YHS Records (Archives), 1937? (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Packing List. Paintings, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Packing List. Pamphlets, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Packing List. Portrait Room House, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Packing List. Pewter & Kindred Objects, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Packing List. Riverdale Museum, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Packing List. Shelf Annex, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Packing List. Shipments to 80th St. & 3rd Ave., 1937? (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Packing List. Silver, 1937? (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Subseries IV.B. Construction Management Documents, 1931, 1935-1939; 2.5 Linear feet in 6 document boxes and one folder of oversize materials
    The subseries is organized in two sets of files. The first set are those that appear to have been maintained by members of Turner Construction Company. The second set are those that appear to have been maintained by Clerk of the Works Garret H. Winter. The files are arranged alphabetically by topic within each set. The topics are believed to be from the original labels.
    The Construction Management Documents subseries includes what appear to be the files of the construction crew, specifically those of representatives of Turner Construction Company, especially Project Superintendent A.C. Gallagher, and Clerk of the Works Garrett H. Winter. There is considerable overlap between this subseries and subseries IV.A., notably with respect to specifications, subcontractor contracts, and project meeting minutes. Nonetheless, this subseries also includes other material, including correspondence among Turner, Winter, the subcontractors, and the architect, Walker & Gillette. The subseries also includes Turner's daily construction progress reports and Winter's diary, or notes, concerning daily developments on the site. There are some photographs of the construction work in progress, various small blueprints and sketches, and brochures from some of the subcontractors.
    - Accounting, circa 1937 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Access Panels, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - ACG [A.C. Gallagher] File, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Includes just a few documents. A.C. Gallagher was Turner's Superintendent on the project.
    - Achilles Construction Co., 1937 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Arches & Fireproofing -- R.E. Carrick & Co., 1937-1938 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Architects' Meeting Minutes (1 of 2), 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Architects' Meeting Minutes (2 of 2), 1938 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Asphalt Tile -- Strawbridge & Clothier, 1937-1938 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Brick, Face, 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Bridge, Sidewalk -- M.F.C. Shoring & Foundation Co., 1937 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Book Stacks, 1937-1938 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Includes photographs of Snead & Co. library furniture products.
    - Book Stack Elevator, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Borings, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Bronze Windows, 1937-1938 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Building Congress, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Cabinet Work, 1938 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Change Orders & Misc., 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Check List [Book Stack Inspection], 1938 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Concrete, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      Includes a booklet "Penn-Dixie Concrete Table and Recommended Mixes for Different Kinds of Work" prepared by the Service Bureau of Pennsylvania-Dixie Cement Corp (New York sales office).
    - Construction Reports (1 of 6), 1937 February-May (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Construction Reports (2 of 6), 1937 June-August (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Construction Reports (3 of 6), 1937 September-December (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Construction Reports (4 of 6), 1938 January-March (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Construction Reports (5 of 6), 1938 April-July (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Construction Reports (6 of 6), 1938 August-October (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Costs, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - [R.L.] Cullum, 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 20)
      Includes correspondence to and from Turner's Project Manager, R.L. Cullum.
    - Distribution [Payroll], 1938 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Doors, 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Door, Overhead -- Allen Automatic Inc., 1937-1938 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Door Trim & Frames (#A1) Index, circa 1937 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Electric, Temporary, 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Electrical Work (1 of 2), 1937-1938 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Electrical Work (2 of 2), 1938 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Elevators, 1937-1938 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Excavations, 1937-1938 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - [File Codes], [1937-1938] (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Includes tables of files coded by plan/drawing number and related creator or sub-contractor. For example, the table indicates that File G-1 relates to granite facing Plan #1 by John L. Goss Corp. The coding relates to those found written on many of the drawings in the series.
    - Flag Pole, 1938 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Formica, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Foundations, 1937-1938 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Glass Block, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      Includes marketing brochure for Insulux glass block from Owens-Illinois Glass Co.
    - Glass -- Contractors Glass Co., 1937-1938 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Granite (1 of 6), 1937 March-August (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Granite (2 of 6), 1937 September (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Granite (3 of 6), 1937 October (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Granite (4 of 6), 1937 November (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Granite (5 of 6), 1937 November-December (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Granite (6 of 6), 1938 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Granite -- Pagano, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Hardware (1 of 4), 1937-1938 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Hardware (2 of 4), 1938 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Hardware (3 of 4), 1938 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Hardware (4 of 4), 1938 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Hardware Schedule, 1938 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Heating, Ventilating, Air Conditioning (1 of 2), 1937 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Heating, Ventilating, Air Conditioning (2 of 2), 1938 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Hoist -- United Hoisting Co., 1937 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Hoist Tower -- Chesbro Whitman, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Hollow Metal Work, 1937-1938 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Hydrolithic Waterproofing, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Insurance Data, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Kalamein Work -- Chapman Metal Products, 1937-1938 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Labor Department, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Lintels -- Van Brunt Bros., 1937 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Lumber, Form, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Marble, 1937-1938 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Mason's Material, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Millwork [Sketches], 1937-38 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Iron, 1937-1938 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Models, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Mosaic Floors & Terrazzo -- Del Turco Bros., 1937-1938 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Nailcrete Corp., circa 1937 (Box 23, Folder 15)
      Includes marketing brochure for Nailcrete Corporation (New York).
    - Oil & Grease, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Painting, 1938 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Partitions (temporary), 1937 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Peelle Doors, 1937 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Plan Notes, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Plans, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Plant & Tools, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 20)
      Includes a marketing brochure for the L. Best Company (New York).
    - Picture Moulding, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Plaster, 1938 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Plumbing, 1937-1938 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Plumbing, Temporary, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Plywood, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Protection of Utilities & Property, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Rolling Shutter Door -- Cornell Iron Works, 1937-1938 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Roofing & Sheet Metal Work, 1937-1938 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Sand -- Materials Delivery Corp., 1937 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Schedule (1 of 3), 1937 (Box 23, Folder 26)
      Includes five photographs of the construction.
    - Schedule (2 of 3), 1938 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Schedule (3 of 3), 1937? (Drawer 12A-B2, Folder 6)
      Includes an oversize blueprint of the progress schedule, dated May 6, 1937, though project timelines go through 1938.
    - Sketches, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Spandrel Beam Waterproofing, 1937 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Specifications, Notes, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Steel, Reinforcement, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Steel, Structural, 1937-1938 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Streets, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 31)
      Includes eleven construction photographs; although these photos seem chiefly interested in the curb line of West 76th and West 77th streets, they include images of the surrounding buildings and part of the sites of demolition.
    - Structural Lintels, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Survey (1 of 2), 1937 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Survey (2 of 2), 1937 (Drawer 12A-B2, Folder 6)
      Includes a blueprint of a survey by George Hollerith.
    - Telephone, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Terra Cotta, Glazed, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Terra Cotta Tile, Rough, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Testing, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Tile Work -- Cranford & Joseph, 1937-1938 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Tracings of Steel Lists (Ordered), 1937 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Vault Door, 1937 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Water, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Westinghouse (1 of 2), 1938 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Westinghouse (2 of 2), 1938 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Window Cleaning, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - Windows, Metal, 1937-1938 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - [Garret H.] Winter, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 43)
      Includes informal notes between Clerk of the Works Winter and Turner's representatives, mostly A.C. Gallagher.
    - Wood Floors, 1937-1938 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Wrecking Subcontract, 1937 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Architect's Specifications, [1937] (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Bulletin, Plant Rental Schedule, 1931, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - [Construction Diary of] Garrett H. Winter (2 notebooks), 1937-1938 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Comparison of Estimates, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Control Panel Wiring Diagrams, Elevator, 1937 (Drawer 12A-B2, Folder 6)
      Includes six photographs of plans by Westinghouse Electric Elevator Co.
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (1 of 9), 1937 January-March (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (2 of 9), 1937 April-June (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (3 of 9), 1937 July-September (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (4 of 9), 1937 October-December (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (5 of 9), 1938 January-March (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (6 of 9), 1938 April-June (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (7 of 9), 1938 July-September (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (8 of 9), 1938 October-December (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (9 of 9), 1939 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Doors & Freight Elevators, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      Includes marketing brochures for The Peelle Company (Brooklyn, NY).
    - Electric Work. Specifications, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Fireproof Floor, Roof Construction, Cinder Fill. Specifications, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Lighting Recommendations, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Metal Lathing & Furring. Specifications, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Minutes, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Lists, 1937?-1938 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Painting. Specifications, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Photographs, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Pier & Foundation Data, 1937 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Plastering. Specifications, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Plumbing Fixtures, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Roofing & Sheet Metal, Structural Steel. Specifications, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Room Finishes, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Schedules. Men in Building, 1935-1937 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Specifications & Conditions of Contract, 1937? (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Specifications. Various (1 of 5), 1937 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Specifications. Various (2 of 5), 1937 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Specifications. Various (3 of 5), 1937 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Specifications. Various (4 of 5), 1937 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Specifications. Various (5 of 5), 1937 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Wrecking Specifications & Bids, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Subseries IV.C. Plans and Drawings, 1925, 1935-1938; 60.73 Linear feet in many oversize folders, 2 flat boxes, 3 document boxes, and 5 rolls of blueprints
    An appointment is required for access to the material in this subseries. Please contact the Print Room at printroom@nyhistory.org.
    The subseries is arranged in alphabetical order by name of the firm that created the plans. [Bracketed names] indicate that the firm's name is not on the document, but was attributed to it by the archivist.